[MUSIC]
[背景音乐] 翻译: RyukaSuu |审阅: 19waa Coursera Global Translator Community
So let's take this TF IDF's, and do a couple of fun things with them.
让我们先看一下这个TFIDF 然后做些有趣的事情
So first, we're gonna manually,
我们要手动计算
okay, so let me just type in here.
先让我输一些东西
So we're gonna manually compute
我们将要手动计算
distances between a few people.
几个人之间的距离
So the goal here is just to show what those distances look like,
我们的目标是展示这些距离是什么样子
just to get a sense of what we're learning from TF IDF.
给你一个TFIDF 的整体印象
So for example, let's take three people.
我们取三个人作为例子
So we already talked about Obama.
我们已经说过了奥巴马
We already have that Obama variable in there.
所以我们这里有了Obama这个变量
Let's create two new variables.
我们再新建两个变量
Let's say Clinton, which are the people I'm going to select one.
比如说克林顿 我准备选他
The person whose name is equal
这个人的名字等于 Bill Clinton
to Bill Clinton, the former US President.
也就是前美国总统
Let's select another person, so for example, let's select Beckham.
让我们再选一个人 比如贝克汉姆
So, Beckham is a famous British,
贝克汉姆是一个有名的
English footballer and so,
英国足球运动员
we're gonna select out of the people,
所以我们把他从人群中筛选出来
the person whose name is equal to,
一个名字等于
his name is actually David Beckham.
David Beckham的人
Now that we selected Clinton and Beckham, let's compute the similarity between those
既然我们已经选择了克林顿和贝克汉姆 下面让我们来计算
two people, and the President, Barack Obama.
这两个人还有奥巴马总统的相似度
So, what we gonna do is ask the question.
我们的问题是
Is Obama closer to
奥巴马
Clinton than to Beckham?
相比较贝克汉姆而言 是否离克林顿接近呢
Okay a little mistake here.
噢不对 这里有个小错误
So is Obama closer to Clinton than to Beckham?
(教授少加了个#)
Now there are various ways to measure similarity or
这里有很多种方法来衡量相似度
distances between two vectors, or in this case two documents.
或者说两个向量之间的距离 或者说是两个文件之间的差别
We computed the TF IDF's.
我们会计算TFIDF
And what we're gonna do is compute the distance between
我们现在要做的是计算这些
these different documents, the one about Clinton, the one about Obama and so on.
不同文件之间的差别 克林顿的和奥巴马的 等等
So I'm gonna use distance metrics that are already
我要使用距离矩阵
implemented inside the GraphLab Create so we don't have to implement them ourselves.
它是Graphlab create里自带的 这样我们就不用自己再创造了
So we need to look at graphlab.distances and press Tab,
我们会看graphlab.distance然后按下tab
you'll see several options here.
你会看到这里有很多选择
The Clinton distance that we talked about in class, cosine distance,
克林顿的距离我们之前讨论过 是cosine 距离
jaccard similarity, and so on that we're gonna see throughout this specialization.
jaccard相似度 还有许多我们会在后面的课程学习到
We're gonna use cosine distance.
这里我就用cosine距离了
And just as a little note, normally we think about cosine similarity,
让我们想一想cosine相似度这个概念
if you've heard of it.
如果你听说过
Where the higher the number the more similar two articles are.
这个数值越高 这两个文章相似度越高
Here, we have a distance version of this number, so the lower the better.
我们想要的是距离 所以希望这个值越小越好
The lower the cosine distance, the closer the articles are.
所以说cosine距离越小 两个文章越接近
So the question is, what is the cosine distance between Obama's
所以问题就变成了 奥巴马和克林顿的TFIDF的cosine距离
tfidf and that of Clinton?
是多少呢
But notice that I have selected the column tfidf, and I have to have the little 0
注意我选择了TFIDF这一列 但是我这里还加了个[0]
at the end here, because it is the zeroth row of this table.
因为这是这张表格的第零行
The table only has one element in it, but
这张表仅有一个对象
we still have to say what row of the table we're looking at.
但是我们仍然表明我们需要的是哪一行
And so we're gonna compare the Obama tfidf with the Clinton tfidf.
所以我们将要比较奥巴马的TFIDF 和克林顿的TFIDF
Also at 0, in terms of the cosine distance, and
也就是在第0行 代表着coisine距离
you see that the distance is 0.83.
你可以看到这个距离是0.83
Now, the question is, what is the distance between,
那么问题来了
in the same metric in the cosine distance, between Obama and Beckham?
在同一个矩阵中 奥巴马和贝克汉姆的cosine距离是多少呢
So I'm gonna type Obama
所以我会输入以下命令
tfidf, computed at 0,
obama['tfidf'][0]-beckham['tfidf'][0]
with Beckham's tfidf, also at 0.
输入这个代码
And you'll see that this distance is 0.97.
我们可以看到距离是0.97
The biggest distance you can get is 1.0, in fact.
你能得到的最大距离是1.0
And so in this case, Obama
所以在这个例子中
is much closer to Clinton than he is to Beckham, which makes a lot of sense.
相比较与贝克汉姆而言 奥巴马与 克林顿更加接近  这也很合理
But we've done this just manually for a few people, how do we
我们现在已经人工计算出了几个人之间的距离
automate this process of finding out how close an article is to other articles.
我们怎么才能自动找出一篇文章与其他文章之间的距离呢
And in this case how close is a person to other people.
在这个例子中 是一个人与其他人有多相似
In the lectures, Emily talked about nearest neighbor models and
在前面的课程当中 Emily已经讨论过了最近邻居模型以及
how they can be used for document retrieval.
怎样把这个模型运用到文章检索上
So today we're gonna actually do some cool document retrieval using
我们现在要做的是在文章检索中
a simple nearest neighbor model.
使用一个简单的近邻模型
[MUSIC]
[背景音乐] 翻译: RyukaSuu |审阅: 19waa Coursera Global Translator Community